# **NLP** engineer

### **Summary**

• Full name: Vadim Polulyakh

• Experience: 10 years

· City: Moscow

#### Core skills

Scala, SciPy, TensorFlow, Natural Language Processing, Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK), Akka, Play Framework, pandas, Apache Spark, Chatbot Development.

# **Projects**

I have developed several projects from scratch, including projects for large companies such as Sberbank, Russian Railways, Rospechat. For example, this one: <a href="http://smartnalog.ru">http://smartnalog.ru</a>. This is a knowledge base on Russian tax law, developed by me from scratch in 3 months. The main challenge of the project was the development of a search engine. This search engine uses AI technologies (USE, ODQA) to select an article from text knowledge base. The question is forwarded to the lawyer if no article is found. Technological stack: python, typescript, tensorflow.

#### **Publications**

date	source	article name
2017	The NIPS '17 Competition: Building Intelligent Systems	Competition on Automatic Evaluation of Dialogue Quality
2018	Radio Metrix	Machine learning in law

# Work history

employment period	name of organization	position	duties/achievements
2017 - 2020	DeepPavlov	chief engineer	We were developing an open-source framework for building chatbots. Our framework includes state-of-the-art NLP models. I leaded the department of business solutions.

https://md2pdf.netlify.com 1/3

employment period	name of organization	position	duties/achievements
2015 - 2017	Raiffeisen Bank	senior lead developer	I was a developer engaged in the development of mission-critical services: authorization, monitoring, and data storage.
2012 - 2015	Edisoft Development Itd.	system architect	Head of the R&D department. I have prototyped several products, e.g. AlfaFactoring platform.
2011 — 2012	Acronis Itd.	software engineer	Participated in the development of Acronis Backup and Recovery for Linux as a regular developer.  Moreover, I was a release manager and manage codebase of the Acronis Backup and Recovery project (~90GB in SVN repo).
2008 - 2010	Moscow Power Engineering Institute	developer	Participated in the development software for the Russian Ministry of Education.

### **Education**

year of graduation	school	degree
2010	MPEI	Masters Degree in Computer Science
2011	udacity.com	Artificial Intelligence
2012	Coursera.org	Software Engineering for SaaS
2013	udacity.com	Artificial Intelligence for Robotics
2014	Coursera.org	Machine Learning
2014	Coursera.org	Functional Programming Principles in Scala
2017	HSE	Masters Degree in Artificial Intelligence

### About me

I am an experienced engineer who has created several large projects from scratch. I will be glad to help you if you need a rapid prototype of an Al-based web service, to solve a practical natural language processing task or to set up a machine learning pipeline.

https://md2pdf.netlify.com 2/3

## **Contacts**

• email: bavadim@gmail.com

• web-site: bavadim.me

• github: github.com/bavadim

https://md2pdf.netlify.com 3/3